Atta Ullah

Office: Room # 97, Hostel 4 Quaid-i-Azam University Islamabad, 45320 Islamabad (Pakistan)

@ attaullah@cs.qau.edu.pk; Homepage Google Scholar GitHub

About

I am currently a final-year master student expected to be graduate in December 2023 from Quaid-i-Azam University, Islamabad, Pakistan. My research area focus on graph machine learning (GML), which is an emerging field having far-reaching applications in a diverse range of industries, from drug discovery and optimization to recommendation and forecasting. We work on conspiracy source detection by considering the propagation pattern of information which spread in the social network. We use graph neural network to embed the propagation pattern and classification the source as real or conspiracy.

Education

M.Phil. Computer Science

Sep. 2021-Present

- Quaid-i-Azam University, Islamabad, Pakistan
- Dissertation: Identifying Misinformation Spreaders on Twitter using Ego-Centric Network Embeddings
- Major Area of Study: Social Network Analysis, Graph Machine Learning
- Minor Area of Study: Artificial Intelligence

BS Computer Science

Aug. 2021

- University Of Swat
- Dissertation: Learning Management System

HSSC Aug. 2017

• Government PG Jahanzeb College Saidu Sharif

Industry Experience

Full Stack Developer

Jan. 2020 - Aug. 2021

Max tech Developers

 As a Full Stack Developer, my primarily role was to develop both the front-end and back-end. The back-end responsibility include database design and implementation and develop an API for extracting data. The front-end responsibility include developing web app (HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript and react) and android app using java and XML. The tool which we used in development include, PHP, Laravel, CodeIgniter, Nodejs, Express js.

Research Experience

Master Student: Quaid-i-Azam University, Islamabad Aug. 2016 - Sep. 2017 Research areas: Conspiracy source detection in social networks, Graph Neural Network

Teaching Experience

Quaid-i-Azam University Teaching Assistant for:

Feb. 2023 - July 2023

- Data structure and Analysis of Algorithms (Spring 2023)
- Problem Solving and Programming (Spring 2023)

Max tech Computer Institute Teaching Assistant for:

- C++ Programming (2020)
- Android App development (2020)

Awards and Honors

Capital University of Science & Technology (CUST), Winner of Hackathon Competition (8th Episode of ExcITeCup 2023), Highest Prize Money Award

Dec. 2019 - Dec 2020

Software Developed

• Learning Management System.

First, the application is functioning as a student record database. administrative authorities can add each and every student's daily record to this system such as classwork is done, Homework assignments, test results, exam results, in school moral/behavioral activities, and physical assessment reports. Moreover, the school management authorities can also publish important notifications about upcoming school events. Secondly, through our proposed application parents can check their children's school activities and full record on daily basis with a single touch, and with comfort on their own preferred timing.

- Thalassemia Centers Management System. (Link to the source code)
- IT Academy Center Institute Management System (Link to the source code)
- Car-Park-Finder (Link to the source code)
- Blood-Donor-Finder (Link to the source code)
- Quiz App (Link to the source code)
- Medicine Order App (Link to the source code)
- Commonwealth toner and ink (Link to the app)
- ZAMA SHOPS Buy & Sell Pakistan (Link to the app)

Certification (courses)

- Java for Android (Coursera)
- Coursera (Coursera)
- Linear Algebra for Machine Learning and Data Science (Coursera)
- Introduction to Docker (Coursera)
- Health Data Science Foundation (Coursera)
- Linear Algebra for Machine Learning and Data Science (Coursera)
- Web Application Technologies and Django (Coursera)
- Crash Course on Python (Coursera)
- Mathematics for Machine Learning: Linear Algebra (Coursera)
- AI for Medical Diagnosis (Coursera)
- Calculus for Machine Learning and Data Science (Coursera)

Programming Tools

• Python, Networkx, TensorFlow, Scikit-learn, PyG, PyTorch, Deep Graph Library, SQL, C++, PHP, Laravel, CodeIgniter, NodeJs, React, JavaScript, Java, Django